Guide to the Larry Polansky Papers MSS.405
Fales Library and Special Collections
- Series IV. Writings and Projects, 1949, 1953, 1976-2013, undated; 21.75 Linear Feet in 4 cartons, 21 manuscript boxes, 6 tall manuscript boxes, 1 flat box, and 3 oversize flat boxes; 20 Gigabytes in 13,106 computer files.; 72 audiocassettes; 24 sound cassettes (dat); 44 Reels; 4 videocassettes (vh
  - Bedhaya Guthrie / Bedhaya Sadra, 1996; cuid25539 (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - Being a Composer in America, 1988; cuid25540 (Box 15, Folder 17)
  - The Best American Poetry You'll Never Read, 2013; cuid25541 (Box 15, Folder 18)
  - The Birth of Peace, 1989; cuid25542 (Box 15, Folder 19)
  - Book Review / Seeker Book / Strauss, 1995-1996; cuid25543 (Box 15, Folder 20)
  - Book Reviews and Editorials, 1987-1999, undated; cuid25544 (Box 15, Folder 21)
  - B'Rey Sheet, 1986, 1990; cuid25545 (Box 15, Folder 22)
  - Bristow-Johnson: JGK + DSP, undated; cuid25546 (Box 15, Folder 23)
  - Brujo / Richard Schwartz, undated; cuid25547 (Box 15, Folder 24)
  - Re: Herbert Brun, undated; cuid25548 (Box 15, Folder 25)
  - Cage 100 Party Pieces Project, 2012; cuid25549 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Cage String Quartet Notes, 1979; cuid25550 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Canon for Flute, 1990; cuid25551 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Catastrophe Theory / Instructions for Actors, undated; cuid25552 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - CD Cover / Proof, 2008; cuid25734 (Box 82, Folder 7)
  - Change Audio CD Master, Tom Erbe, 2002; cuid25919 (Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_405_ER_58)
  - Cocks Crow, Dogs Bark: New Compositional Intentions, 1997; cuid25553 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Cold Blue Two / CD, 2012; cuid25554 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Composing and Related Theoretical Work / Guggenheim Application, 1991; cuid25555 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Computer Pieces: Sketch, undated; cuid25556 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Computer Program Flow Chart, undated; cuid25735 (Box 82, Folder 8)
  - Computer Program Project Printout, 1976; cuid25677 (Box 75, Folder 3-5)
  - Computer Programing Notes for Works, 2009; cuid25557 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Contemporary and Experimental Indonesian Music / Guest Hosts on KXE Radio Show, 1991; cuid25558 (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Contracts, 1984-2013; cuid25559 (Box 16, Folder 11-12)
  - Cristobal Colon Text for Dance Piece for Andrea Smith / Indonesia, 1989; cuid25560 (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - Dear. John, 2003; cuid25561 (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - Delicate Computations with Philip Comer, 1987; cuid25562 (Box 16, Folder 15)
  - Digital Archives from Tom Erbe, 2000-2011; cuid25893 (Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_405_ER_18)
  - Dissonant Counterpoint and Statistical Feedback, 2007-2008; cuid25563 (Box 16, Folder 16)
  - Distance Music I - VI, Fair Copy, 1987; cuid25564 (Box 16, Folder 17)
  - DIY Canons CD Liner Notes, 2005; cuid25565 (Box 16, Folder 18)
  - Duet Printouts Computer, 1990; cuid25566 (Box 16, Folder 19)
  - Editing, Reviewing, Blurbs, 2003, 2009-2011, undated; cuid25567 (Box 16, Folder 20)
  - Editorials, Letters to the Editor, 1987-1999, 2007; cuid25568 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Eine Kleine, 1995-2007; cuid25569 (Box 17, Folder 2, Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_405_ER_19, E-records FA_MSS_405_ER_59)
  - Electronic Music / Cassette Notes, 1970s; cuid25570 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - End Notes: 17 for the 36 A Hymn, 1978; cuid25571 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Envisioning Ruth Crawford Seeger's Piano Study...Society of Music Theory, Montreal / Presentation, 1993; cuid25572 (Box 17, Folder 5-6)
  - Experimental Intermedia Foundation Program Notes, Master, 1988, 1991; cuid25573 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - A Few More Words about Jim Tenney..., 2010; cuid25733 (Box 82, Folder 9)
  - A Few More Words on Jim Tenney..., 2008-2010; cuid25575 (Box 17, Folder 9-11)
  - A Few Words about Jim Tenney, 2006-2007; cuid25574 (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Field Recording: Medan Talk, 1989; cuid25576 (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - Fifty Miles of Elbow Room and Other Music, circa 1978-1980; cuid25736 (Box 82, Folder 10)
  - Flexible Orchestra, 2004-2009; cuid25920 (Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_405_ER_60)
  - Follow the Many Paths Together Poem / Haiga, 1981; cuid25577 (Box 17, Folder 13)
  - Fontana Mix / Matiner Score, 2007; cuid25578 (Box 17, Folder 14)
  - Four Voice Canons CD, 2002; cuid25579 (Box 17, Folder 15)
  - Frengelmusic Code and Data, 2001; cuid25580 (Box 17, Folder 16)
  - Fuging Tune in G, 1981; cuid25581 (Box 17, Folder 17)
  - The Future of Music, 1987; cuid25582 (Box 17, Folder 18)
  - Gamelan and Guitar Canon, 2002; cuid25895 (Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_405_ER_20)
  - Gaussian Computation, 2005; cuid25583 (Box 17, Folder 19)
  - Haiku for Charles D., 1999; cuid25584 (Box 17, Folder 20)
  - Haiku for Nick, Leslie, and Nora, 1993; cuid25585 (Box 17, Folder 21)
  - Haikus and Haigas, 1979-1992; cuid25586 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Harry Partch Transcription Project, 1979-1981, 1980s; cuid25587 (Box 18, Folder 3-11)
  - Harry Potter Musical (School Play), 2001; cuid25588 (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - A Hierarchical Gestalt Analysis of Ruggles' Portals, 1978; cuid25591 (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - History and the Word: Form and Tonality in Schoenberg's Phantasy..., 1982, 1985; cuid25592 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - HMSL: A Theoretical Overview / Articles, 1990; cuid25589 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - HMSL (Hierarchical Music Specification Language), 1981-2004, undated; cuid25590 (Box 18, Folder 13-19, Box 19, Folder 1-10)
  - HODOS Research Paper with James Tenney, 1976-1977; cuid25593 (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Howard Skempton Arrangment by Polansky, 1998, undated; cuid25737 (Box 82, Folder 11)
  - ICMA (International Computer Music Association) Cyber Quilt CD-ROM Project, 1998; cuid25594 (Box 20, Folder 3, Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_405_ER_17)
  - If We Can Make It We Can Print It..., 1992; cuid25595 (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Indonesia / Gamelan Project, 1988-1989; cuid25596 (Box 20, Folder 5-11)
  - Interval Sizes in Javanese Slendro, 1985; cuid25597 (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Interview with David Rosenboom, 1983; cuid25598 (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Invertebrate Topology Instructions for Actors, undated; cuid25599 (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Io Album, 2008-2009; cuid25600 (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Jaki Final Source Listing, undated; cuid25675 (Box 75, Folder 1)
  - James Tenney: Postal Pieces Liner Notes, 2003; cuid25601 (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Joan Sound Recordings, 2001; cuid25896 (Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_405_ER_23)
  - Just Intonation Network, 1984-1986; cuid25602 (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Jim Horton Project, 2006; cuid25894 (Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_405_ER_22)
  - K-Toods Recording Session Notes, 2012; cuid25603 (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - Labels for Cassettes, 1988, undated; cuid25604 (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - Larry Polansky: The World's Longest Melody, 2010; cuid25605 (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - Leonardo Music Journal, 1988-1997; cuid25606 (Box 21, Folder 10-12)
  - Lerman / 17BH, 1997; cuid25607 (Box 21, Folder 13)
  - Let's Build a Railroad Event, 2001; cuid25608 (Box 21, Folder 14, Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_405_ER_35)
  - Letters to the Editor on Adoption, 1993; cuid25609 (Box 21, Folder 15)
  - Life in Shadows, Forward, 2009; cuid25610 (Box 21, Folder 16)
  - Liner Notes for David Mahler's Artifact CD, 1997; cuid25611 (Box 21, Folder 17)
  - Liner Notes for Other CDs, 1997; cuid25612 (Box 21, Folder 18)
  - Live Interactive Computer Music in HMSL, 1984-1992, 1991, 1994; cuid25613 (Box 21, Folder 19)
  - Mahler Session Log, 2004; cuid25614 (Box 21, Folder 20)
  - Margaret Lancaster Data Raw Samples, 2000; cuid25897 (Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_405_ER_24)
  - A Mathematical Model for Optimal Tuning Systems, 2008-2009; cuid25615 (Box 22, Folder 1-3)
  - Metrics, 1990, 1994, undated; cuid25616 (Box 22, Folder 4-5)
  - Metrics Notes, September 1988, Indonesia, cuid25738 (Box 82, Folder 12)
  - Miscellaneous, 1983-1989; cuid25617 (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Miscellaneous Sketches, Covers, Etc. Sacco...Conductor Score / C, L'Man... Mando Cello Part / Other Odd Stuff, 1982, undated; cuid25739 (Box 82, Folder 13)
  - Miscellaneous Writings, 1979-1994, undated; cuid25618 (Box 22, Folder 7-8)
  - More on Morphological Mutation Functions..., circa 1992; cuid25619 (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - Morphological Metrics, 1987-1996; cuid25620 (Box 22, Folder 10-12)
  - Movie Script with Edits re: Music, undated; cuid25621 (Box 22, Folder 13)
  - Music and Computers: A Theoretical and Historical Approach / Sales Data and Course Guide, 2005-2008; cuid25622 (Box 22, Folder 14)
  - Music and Computers Book Sales Data, 2008; cuid25898 (Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_405_ER_25)
  - The Music of American Folk Song, 1953-2005, undated; cuid25623 (Box 26, Folder 1-11, Box 27, Folder 1-8, Box 28, Folder 1-10, Box 29, Folder 1-9, Box 30, Box 31, Folder 7, Box 82, Folder 14, Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_405_ER_38)
  - The Music of American Folk Song Talk Audio Samples, 2001-2005; cuid25921 (Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_405_ER_61)
  - The Music of James Tenney, 1984; cuid25877 (Box 57, Folder 11)
  - The Music of the Voyager Interstellar Record, 1993; cuid25624 (Box 22, Folder 15)
  - Music Works Article, 2001; cuid25905 (Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_405_ER_33)
  - Musician List with Minutes, Times, undated; cuid25625 (Box 22, Folder 16)
  - Names List, undated; cuid25740 (Box 82, Folder 15)
  - Nagorcka Prelude, 2002; cuid25899 (Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_405_ER_26, E-records FA_MSS_405_ER_62)
  - Nancarrow: The Lost Rolls, 1992-1996; cuid25901 (Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_405_ER_28)
  - Nancarrow: Player Piano Studies, 1992-1996; cuid25900 (Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_405_ER_27)
  - New Music Commissioning Project, Master, 1991; cuid25626 (Box 22, Folder 17)
  - New Music for Plucked Strings Program Notes, 1985; cuid25627 (Box 22, Folder 18)
  - Night Hunter Movie Soundtrack, 2010-2011; cuid25628 (Box 23, Folder 1, Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_405_ER_29, E-records FA_MSS_405_ER_70)
  - No Replacement (85 Verses for Kenneth Gaburo), 1995; cuid25629 (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Notation (Published? For What?), undated; cuid25630 (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Notebook, 1977-1983; cuid25631 (Box 23, Folder 4-5)
  - Notes, 1984, 2004-2011, undated; cuid25632 (Box 23, Folder 6-9)
  - Notes on Will You Miss Me, 2007; cuid25633 (Box 23, Folder 10)
  - Nothing Like Dreaming Movie Project, 1994-2004; cuid25902 (Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_405_ER_30)
  - On the Nature of Rounds, undated; cuid25634 (Box 23, Folder 11)
  - Optimal Well-Temperament..., 1998-2006; cuid25635 (Box 23, Folder 12-13)
  - Orpheus Research Centre in Music, Research Festival, Mention, 2011; cuid25636 (Box 23, Folder 14)
  - OWT: A Real-Time Optimal Tuning Application, 2008; cuid25637 (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Palm Boulevard by Alexis Alrich for Larry Polansky, 1985; cuid25638 (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Partch (Harry) Transcription Project, 1980-1981; cuid25725 (Box 81, Folder 1-2)
  - Partch (Harry) Transcriptions, 1970s, undated; cuid25639 (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - Partch (Harry) Transcriptions Letters, Research, 1949-1977; cuid25640 (Box 24, Folder 4-6)
  - Patch IV / Program / Manual, 1978-1979; cuid25641 (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - Peruvian Revolutionary Leader to Speak...by Polansky(?), undated; cuid25642 (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - Philosophy 3 Video, 2001; cuid25903 (Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_405_ER_31)
  - The Player Piano Project, undated; cuid25925 (Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_405_ER_66)
  - Pogus Productions: White Fungus Compilation, 2010; cuid25643 (Box 24, Folder 9)
  - Polansky Album - Description, Notes, undated; cuid25644 (Box 24, Folder 10)
  - Polansky Scores (Music Press), 1999-2002; cuid25906 (Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_405_ER_34)
  - Possible and Impossible Melody..., 1991-1992; cuid25645 (Box 24, Folder 11-12)
  - Problem for Larry Polansky / J. Tenney, undated; cuid25726 (Box 81, Folder 3)
  - Programming, etc.: Midi, Soundhack, OMS, CSound, Macos, OSP, undated; cuid25646 (Box 24, Folder 13)
  - Psalms Translation Notes, undated; cuid25647 (Box 24, Folder 14)
  - Recording Notes, 1997; cuid25727 (Box 81, Folder 4)
  - Recording Session Notes -- Carry Me Long/The Challenge Album, 1981, 1983; cuid25867 (Box 84, Folder 4)
  - Recording Session Notes / Unknown, undated; cuid25648 (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Rhythms of the Tarkine, 2004; cuid25922 (Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_405_ER_63)
  - Richard Zvonar Interview, 1984; cuid25649 (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Ruth Crawford Seeger Piece, When, Not If, 2001; cuid25923 (Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_405_ER_64)
  - Sacred Heart Singing, undated; cuid25650 (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Sante Fe Institute / 2 Talks on Music and Mathematics, 2006; cuid25651 (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Scores for Tintinnabulate Concert, performance, undated; cuid25652 (Box 25, Folder 27)
  - Seventeen Thoughts on 'Music since 1960', 1994; cuid25653 (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Shemot, 2010; cuid25654 (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - Simple Actions, circa 1987; cuid25655 (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - A Small Book of Rounds..., 2007, 2010; cuid25656 (Box 25, Folder 8-9)
  - Sound Files, 2002; cuid25907 (Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_405_ER_36)
  - Sound Recording Mixes, 2000-2002; cuid25924 (Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_405_ER_65)
  - Sound Recordings on Audiocassette -- Fellowship Projects, Studio Sessions, and Albums, 1977-1999; cuid25861 (Box 97, Box 100, Box 101)
  - Sound Recordings on Digital Audio Tape (DAT), 1988-2002; cuid25865 (Box 103)
  - Sound Recordings on Open Reel, 1973-1978, 1984-1989; cuid25871 (Box 104, Box 105, Box 106, Box 108, Box 109, Box 110, Box 112, Box 113, Box 114)
    1" Open Reel (Audio), Count: 3 1/4" Open Reel (Audio), Count: 41
  - Soundhack / Mutation Connecticut (Conference), 1994, 1995; cuid25657 (Box 25, Folder 10)
  - Sounds, 1993-1999; cuid25908 (Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_405_ER_37)
  - Spectral Mutation in Soundhack, 1996; cuid25658 (Box 25, Folder 11)
  - Steppin' Out / Instructions for Dance Performance, 1978; cuid25659 (Box 25, Folder 12)
  - Sticky Melodies, Johanna Beyer CD / Polansky Edits, 2008; cuid25660 (Box 25, Folder 13)
  - Studies Printouts, 1990; cuid25661 (Box 25, Folder 14)
  - Suite for Bass Clarinet and Piano / Reviewer Notes from Polansky, 2002; cuid25663 (Box 25, Folder 16)
  - Temporal Gestalt Perception in Music (James Tenney with Polansky), 1980; cuid25664 (Box 25, Folder 17)
  - Tenney Book Introduction, Nothing is Yet Known about Structural..., 2012; cuid25665 (Box 25, Folder 18)
  - Tenney: OP (Some Notes on Available Materials By and About James Tenney), undated; cuid25666 (Box 25, Folder 19)
  - Tenney Theoretical Writings, Book Review Revisions, 2012; cuid25667 (Box 25, Folder 20)
  - Tenny Book Examples / MSS, undated; cuid25676 (Box 75, Folder 2)
  - The Theory of Impossible Melody / CD, 2009; cuid25668 (Box 25, Folder 21)
  - Time is Now / CD Notes, etc., 1996; cuid25669 (Box 25, Folder 22)
  - To Larry from Phil, 2008, 2010; cuid25889 (Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_405_ER_12)
  - Total Eclipse: The Music of Johanna Magdalena Beyer, 1996; cuid25670 (Box 25, Folder 23)
  - A Tribute to James Tenney / Various Writings from Perspectives of New Music, 1987; cuid25671 (Box 25, Folder 24)
  - Trio, 1999-2010; cuid25904 (Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_405_ER_39, E-records FA_MSS_405_ER_67)
  - Trios / CD, 2000, 2010-2011; cuid25672 (Box 25, Folder 25)
  - Trumpet Samples with Ed Carroll, 2001; cuid25909 (Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_405_ER_40)
  - Tuning Systems in American Gamelan, 1985; cuid25673 (Box 25, Folder 26)
  - White Fungus Compilation, 2009; cuid25926 (Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_405_ER_68)
- Series V. Teaching and Appearances, 1975-2013, undated; 10.25 Linear Feet in 4 record cartons, 9 manuscript boxes, 6 tall manuscript boxes; 1 Gigabytes in 210 computer files.; 97 audiocassettes; 28 Reels; 5 videocassettes (vhs); 4 videocassettes (betamax)
  This series includes material accumulated by Polansky while teaching at Mills College and Dartmouth College, as well as work files for external lectures, panels, and conferences he participated in. The Mills College files in this series contain lecture notes and slides for music theory and composition classes; planning notes for student concerts; class evaluations; and music department files. Audio recordings from 1981 to 1990 for the Mills College Contemporary Music Seminar in Formal Methods Series are also in this series. This series also contain Polansky's Dartmouth College Music Department files which include tests, class evaluations, tenure correspondence, and a poster for Polansky's 2013 retirement. Of note is correspondence, clippings, and student lists related to Polansky's class on American Sign Language (ASL) and poetry offered in the 1990s. Also included in this series are bound copies of course readings for classes from the 1990s and 2000s. Paper and electronic files for conference, festival, and lecture preparation material, notes, and slides can also be found in this series. Of note is International Computer Music Association/Conference material from the 1980s and 1990s. Concert ephemera for Mills College and Dartmouth College, as well as select conference and festival material can be found in Series II.
  Arranged in alphabetical order by file title.
  - Audiovisual Recordings, 1982-2001; cuid25874 (Box 115)
    VHS, Count: 5
    Betamax, Count: 4
  - Australia Tour 1 Visit, 1988-1996; cuid25745 (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - Beyond Imprimature Presentation, 1992; cuid25746 (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - Bibliography of Musical Form, circa 1983; cuid25747 (Box 32, Folder 3)
  - Class Lecture Notes, etc., 2011-2012, undated; cuid25748 (Box 32, Folder 4)
  - Columbia Colloquia, circa 2005; cuid25749 (Box 32, Folder 5)
  - Composition Class Schedule, undated; cuid25750 (Box 32, Folder 6)
  - Dartmouth College Department of Music, 1989-2013; cuid25751 (Box 32, Folder 7-14, Box 33, Folder 1-14, Box 34, Folder 1-7)
  - Drums Along the Pacific Festival Presentation, 2009; cuid25752 (Box 34, Folder 8)
  - Educom Talk / Computer Music Pedagogy / Lecture Notes, 1985; cuid25753 (Box 35, Folder 1)
  - Electro-Acoustic Music at Dartmouth: The Bregman Studio, undated; cuid25910 (Box Electronic Records, E-records FA_MSS_405_ER_41)
  - Experiment / Class Reading, undated; cuid25754 (Box 35, Folder 2)
  - Fluxus Concert Ideas and Class, 2011; cuid25755 (Box 35, Folder 3)
  - Form and Lecture Slides, 1990, undated; cuid25756 (Box 35, Folder 4)
  - Grant Proposals for Mills College and Early Dartmouth College, 1985-1995; cuid25757 (Box 35, Folder 5)
  - Handouts, undated; cuid25758 (Box 35, Folder 6)
  - Harp Transparencies and Lecture Slides, undated; cuid25759 (Box 35, Folder 7)
  - Hebrew Arts School Agreement, 1981; cuid25760 (Box 35, Folder 8)
  - Hensley Lecture Notes, undated; cuid25761 (Box 35, Folder 9)
  - Hierarchical Music Specification Language (HMSL) / Symposium Presentation Abstract, 1988; cuid25762 (Box 35, Folder 10)
  - Holocaust Music Talk, 1994; cuid25763 (Box 35, Folder 11)
  - Humanities Research Institute / Presentation Notes, Slides, 1998; cuid25764 (Box 35, Folder 12)
  - International Computer Music Association (ICMA) Notes, 1998; cuid25765 (Box 36, Folder 3)
  - International Computer Music Conference (ICMC), 1991-1998, 2006; cuid25766 (Box 35, Folder 13-17, Box 36, Folder 1-2)
  - Introduction to Composers and Theorists in Dialog / Panel, 1996; cuid25767 (Box 36, Folder 4)
  - Javanese Music Lecture Slides, 1993; cuid25768 (Box 36, Folder 5)
  - Math Colloquium Xeroxes / Presentation, 2000; cuid25769 (Box 36, Folder 6)
  - Metatheory Lecture Slides, 1990, undated; cuid25770 (Box 36, Folder 7)
  - Metrics Talk Lecture Slides, 1991-1996; cuid25771 (Box 36, Folder 8)
  - Mills College Center for Contemporary Music, 1978-2013; cuid25772 (Box 36, Folder 9-15, Box 37, Folder 1-20, Box 38, Folder 1)
  - Mills College Center for Contemporary Music Seminar in Formal Methods Series -- Sound Recordings on Audiocassette, 1981-1990; cuid25856 (Box 95, Box 96)
    Audiocassette tapes.
  - Milton Avery Graduate School of the Arts (Faculty), 2005; cuid25773 (Box 38, Folder 2)
  - Morph Orders Graph and Histograms of Uniform Distributions, undated; cuid25774 (Box 38, Folder 3)
  - Music 148 Readings, undated; cuid25775 (Box 38, Folder 4-5)
  - Music 2 Syllabus Lecture Slides, 1996; cuid25776 (Box 38, Folder 6)
  - Music in and About Shoah -- Lecture Notes, Slides, 1996; cuid25777 (Box 38, Folder 7)
  - Music Making, Music Listening Chart, 2004; cuid25778 (Box 38, Folder 8)
  - Mutation Melody, 1991-1992; cuid25779 (Box 38, Folder 9)
  - New Music Commissioning Project and Indonesia Lecture Slides, undated; cuid25780 (Box 38, Folder 10)
  - Notation Exercise Notes, undated; cuid25781 (Box 38, Folder 11)
  - Notes, Dartmouth Student "Inspiration" Panel, 2011; cuid25782 (Box 38, Folder 12)
  - Notes, Meeting, Opening for Concert, 2009; cuid25783 (Box 38, Folder 13)
  - Orpheus Talk -- Why Not Use a Pencil..., 2011; cuid25784 (Box 38, Folder 14)
  - Personal and Lecture Notes, 1983-1986, undated; cuid25785 (Box 38, Folder 15)
  - RCS (Ruth Crawford Seeger) The Music of American Folk Song Talk, 2001; cuid25786 (Box 38, Folder 16)
  - Rhythmicana Lecture Slides, undated; cuid25787 (Box 38, Folder 17)
  - Schedules for Trips and Appearances, undated; cuid25788 (Box 38, Folder 18)
  - Scholz: Economy and Frog Peak Collabs Text Lecture Slides, 1996-1997, undated; cuid25789 (Box 38, Folder 19)
  - Sonneck Society Festival of New Music Talk, 1985; cuid25790 (Box 38, Folder 20)
  - Sound Recordings on Audiocassette -- Lectures and Radio Interviews, 1978-1989; cuid25857 (Box 96)
  - Sound Recordings on Open Reel, 1975-1986; cuid25873 (Box 106, Box 107, Box 108, Box 109, Box 110, Box 111, Box 112, Box 113, Box 114)
    1/4" Open Reel (Audio), Count: 28
  - Talk Notes for MacDowell, 2010; cuid25791 (Box 38, Folder 21)
  - Tenney, Polansky Schedule at York and Toronto, 1990; cuid25792 (Box 38, Folder 22)
  - TMJ Transparencies Lecture Slides, undated; cuid25793 (Box 38, Folder 23)
- Series VI. Personal, 1937-ongoing; 16.25 Linear Feet in 33 manuscript boxes, 1 flat box, and 1 oversize flat box; 126 Gigabytes in 112,457 computer files.; 641 audiocassettes; 30 sound cassettes (dat); 1 websites in 1 archived website.